so what does the e state do the M State
gives us exclusive access so we can both
read and write and makes us the owner of
a dirty block so that we have to respond
with the data and also update memory the
S state gives us shared access so that
we can only read and we are not
responsible for giving others our data
and also we are not responsible for
updating memory we have seen that the
old state also gives us shared access so
we can do reads
but makes us responsible for updating
memory and giving data to others so that
we avoid memory rights that occur when
we don't have this state what it does is
it gives us exclusive so that we can
read and write
although the block is still clean the
memory still doesn't need to be updated
so when acordes read a followed by write
a in the MSI protocol we move from
invalid to shared and suffer a mess and
then we move from shared to modified and
need to send out an invalidation so we
had to bus accesses if we have the M o
si we have the same sequence because
really the old state is not helping us
here it's helping us save memory axises
after we had a write and other start
reading if we have the m es i with no o
state or a protocol that combines all of
the states when we do a read we now
detect that although we have read the
block we are the only one having it so
instead of going to the shared state we
go to the e state and we suffer a miss
but the idea now is that when our right
to a occurs we know we have exclusive
access so we can just write without
telling anybody although we have to
transition to the end state now because
now the block is also dirty so now we
get the same behavior that we would get
if we did the sequence of accesses on a
cash-in a uniprocessor so this is not a
shared block here and we want to get the
same number of missed
and accesses as we do in a uniprocessor
that doesn't share data so here we will
have a Miss followed by a cache hit we
want to have a cache hit here and the
east state allows us to achieve that